Harris, Raymond and Sara; Papers apap378
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Raymond and Sara Harris Papers
1942-2009
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap378
15.7 cubic ft.
This collection documents the personal and professional lives of Dr. Raymond and Sara Harris and their involvment in the Albany, N.Y. community.
Acess
Access to this collection is unrestricted except for some folders (noted on the finding aid) that contain personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The children of Raymond and Sara Harris donated all materials in the collection to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in 2018 and 2024.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in six series. All are arranged alphabetically.
Biographical / Historical
Dr. Raymond and Sara Harris were active members of the Albany, N.Y. community. In 1957, the couple co-founded the Center for the Study of Aging of Albany, N.Y.
Dr. Raymond Harris was born in Brooklyn, N.Y. on June 26, 1919. A graduate of Cornell University and Albany Medical College, Harris also served in the Army Medical Corps at the Walter Reed Hospital during the Second World War. Dr. Harris, a published author and seasoned lecturer, was the chief of the sub-department of Cardiovascular Medicine at St. Peters Hospital in Albany and sat on various medical boards throughout his medical career including Albany Med and the Ann Lee Home. Dr. Harris was also involved in the general field of gerontology and hosted many programs and events. Elected president of the Albany Jewish Community Center, Dr. Harris was an active member of the Albany community until his death on August 25, 1989.
Sara Harris was born Sara Hilda Richman in Cleveland, Ohio in 1921. After attending Girls Latin School in Boston, Harris graduated from the University of Chicago and went on to study at the Arts Students League in New York City. Also an active member in the Albany community, Harris was the executive director of the Center for the Study of Aging of Albany, a member of the board of directors for the Albany Inter-Racial Council, and founder of the local Red Cross Friendly Visiting Service. Sara Harris was also a prominent artist in the area and nominated for awards for her skills in painting and drawing. Sara Harris enjoyed writing poetry and published a book on exercise for people over 50. She died on May 15, 2016.
Raymond and Sara Harris were survived by their four children, two sons and two daughters, and grandchildren.
Content Description
This collection documents the professional and personal lives of Dr. Raymond and Sara Harris and their work in the Albany community through St. Peters Hospital, Albany Medical Hospital, the Center for the Study of Aging of Albany N.Y., the Albany Inter-Racial Council, and the Albany Jewish Community Center. Materials consist of published articles, books, correspondence, hospital records, lecture notes, various council meeting minutes, studies on gerontology, newsletters, and family history. The collection also contains audio and visual material related to the field of gerontology.
Separated Materials
The archivist transferred several monographs by Raymond Harris: Clinical Geriatric Cardiology: Managment of the Elderly Patient, The Management of Geriatric Cardiovascular Disease (in English and Chinese), and Geriatric Medicine: The Treatment of Disease in the Elderly and Sara Harris Lifelong Health and Fitness, Volume I: Prevention and Human Aging edited with Willard S. Harris and Jonathan O. Harris and Who? Me?! Exercise?: Safe Exercise for People Over 50 co-authored with Olga Hurley, as well as the three-volume set Physical Activity, Aging and Sports edited by Raymond and Sara Harris,to the book division of Special Collections. They will all be catalogued and included in the University Library Catalog.
Medical care; Harris, Raymond, 1919-1989; Harris, Sara, 1921-; Gerontology; Albany (N.Y.); Medicine and Health Care; Albany, New York; Correspondence.; Medical records; Serials (publications); Lectures; Minutes (administrative records); Files by subject
- Biographical, 1942-2007; 2.2 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains personal correspondence, personal documents, and photographs of Raymond and Sara Harris. Included in the correspondence are letters to their children, their friends, and other members of their immediate family. There are family updates in the correspondence and poetry written by Sara Harris. The series also contains information on the lesiure activities enjoyed by the Harris family such as tennis games. The series also features documents related to the couples' involvement in the Albany Jewish Community Center and their temple. The series features information on Raymond Harris's service in the U.S. Army, as well as records of the art shows Sara Harris participated in.
  - 1974 Exhibition by Artists of the Mohawk-Hudson (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Albany Artists Group, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Albany Artists Group - 60th Anniversary Celebration, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Albany Jewish Community Center, 1963; 1966; 1968-1969; 1971-1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Army Papers - Raymond Harris, 1942-1949; 1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Award - American Biographical Institute - Sara Harris, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Berkshire Art Association - Fourth Annual Exhibition, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Birthday Cards, 1962; 1979; Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - Raymond Harris' Parents, 1962-1965; 1972; 1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Designs for Copper Jewelry for Sara Harris, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence with Children, 1968-1969; 1973-1980; 1982; 1984; Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence, 1955-2007 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Gowers - Literature Writing, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Harlem Valley Psychiatric Center - Sara Harris Paychecks - RESTRICTED, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Must consult an archivist before viewing.
  - Headshots, 1962-1985 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - ICG - Attention Young People, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Inaugural Parade Honoring Governor Milton J. Shapp and Lieutenant Governor Ernest P. Kline, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Ledgers, 1961; Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - List of Donations-Sara Harris, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Medical Resignation, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Medical School Letters for Jonathan Harris, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - National Service Agency for Jewish Community Centers and Military Families, 1977-1978; Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Our Lady of Mercy Guild Perpetual Membership - Raymond Harris, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Partial Listing of Voluntary Activities of Dr. Harris and Affiliations, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Passports, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Personal Calendars, 1972-1973 (Flat-file 4)
  - Personal Correspondence with Otto Luening, 1986-1988 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Photos of Raymond Harris, Sara Harris, Friends, and Family (1 of 2), 1946-1985 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Photos of Raymond Harris, Sara Harris, Friends, and Family (2 of 2), 1946-1985 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Poems - Sara Harris, 1976; 2000-2001; Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Professional Entertainment, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Raymond Harris - Obituaries, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Raymond Harris - Paychecks - RESTRICTED, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Recipes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Remembrance, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Rotary Club of Schenectady East - Sara Harris, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Sara Harris - Birth Certificate, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Sara Harris in the News, 1955; 1960 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Saratoga Lake Sailing Club, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Schenectady Art Show - The Paintings and Drawings of Sara Harris, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Seasons Greetings, 1966-2001 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Temple Israel, 1962; 1966; 1977 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Tennis Club - Sara Harris, 1975-1977; Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Tom Sawyer Nine - Paintings by Sara Harris, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - University of Chicago - Sara Harris - RESTRICTED, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Voluntary Activities - Sara Harris, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Medical Papers, 1944-2000; 3.6 cubic ft.
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  This series contains the medical files and publications of Raymond Harris during his tenure in the medical community. Raymond Harris was a cardiologist at St. Peters Hospital in Albany, N.Y. and sat on a variety of committees and boards. Dr. Harris also was on staff at Albany Medical Hospital and the Ann Lee Home. Raymond Harris also worked at a psychiatric hospital and was a consultant on various medical cases. Included in this series are medical publications, documents related to the various hospitals and other institutions where Raymond Harris worked, and correspondence between colleagues. Some files containing patient information are restricted.
  - 1977 Annual Scientific Sessions of the American College of Cardiology, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1987 Walter M. Beatle Jr. Distinguished Service Award in Aging-Nomination Form (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Abstract for Gerentological Society Meeting, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - ACC News: Annual Meeting Highlights, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Advances in Medical Care of the Elderly, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Aging Heart: Insight into Biologic Changes and their Clinical Significance, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Aging is a Life Long Process, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Aging of the Cardiovascular System, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Albany County Heart Association - Meeting Minutes of the Research and Fellowship Allocations committee, 1963 January 30 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Albany County Heart Association - Meeting Minutes of the Research and Fellowship Allocations committee, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Albany County Nursing Home/Ann Lee Home, 1959; 1964-1965; 1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Albany County Nursing Home/Ann Lee Home - Medical Evaluation -Medical Plan of Care, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Albany County Nursing Home/Anne Lee Home - Termination of Dr. Harris, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Albany Junior Chamber of Commerce - Man of the Month, 1954 March 10 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Albany Medical Center Hospital - By Laws Rules and Regulation, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Albany Medical Center Hospital Staff Committees, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Albany Regional Mental Health Planning Committee - Meeting Minutes, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Albany Regional Mental Health Planning Committee - Report of the Subcommittee on Rehabilitation, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Alex Haley Gerontology Award - Nomination Form, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "Alienation Emotional Decay in "Golden Years", 1974 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Allergic Diseases of the Cardiovascular System, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Allied Health Personnel: Some Problems, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - American and European Research Committee - Seventh International Congress of Gerontology, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - American Board of Internal Medicine - Passing of Oral Examination, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - American Heart Association - Council on Community Service and Education - Recommendations of the Rehabilitation Committee for a Five Year Plan, 1957-1961 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - American Journal of Cardiology, 1959-1969 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - The American Orthopsychiatric Association, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - A.N, Bardy Hospital - Committees, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Angiology Research Foundation Award, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Ann Lee Moreland Commission, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Annual Report - Peripheral Vascular Section, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Application for Registration Under Controlled Substance Act of 1970 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Appointments, 1954; 1958; 1961-1970; 1972-1973; 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Assessing the Cardiac Patient for Rehabilitation, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Attitudes Toward Living and Death in Chronic Cardiovascular Disease, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Barriers to Health Care of Older Americans, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Biomedical Photo Library, Undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - The Birthday Party, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Body and Mind, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Book Reviews, 1962-1986 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Breaking the Barriers to Better Health Care Delivery for the Aged, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - By Laws of the Medical Staff of the A.N. Brady Hospital and St. Catherine Home, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Cardiac Arrest Program, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Cardiac Arrhythmias, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Cardiac Arrhythmias in the Aged, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Cardiac Changes with Age, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Cardiac Problems: Treating the Geriatric Patient, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Cardiac Rehabilitation: Cardiac Paradox of the Senior Citizen, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Cardiopathy of Aging - An Entity or Amalgamation, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Cardiovascular Changes with Age, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Cardiovascular Diseases in the Aged, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Cardiovascular Rehabilitation: The Role of the New York State Heart Assembly, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Cardiovascular Spotlight - Cardiovascular Rehabilitation the Role of the New York State Heart Assembly, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Cardiovascular System in Rehabilitation of the Elderly, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - The Care and Protection of Your Heart, Undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Caring for an Aging Population, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Catch-22 Situation, Undated (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Certificate of Registration - Authority to Practice the Procession of Physician and Surgeon, 1945 June 6 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Circulatory Disorders (Blood-Pressure Problems), 1975 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Clinical Evaluation of a New Buffered Aspirin Phenacetin and Caffeine Analgesia, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Clinical Observation of Amotriphene Hydrochloride, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Clinical Significance of the Presystolic Wave in the Cartid Arterial Pulse Tracing, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Clinical Trends in Cardiology, 1976 (Flat-file 1)
  - Committee to Study Need for Institute for Children Crippled with Cardiac Disease - Albany Heart Association, 1952; 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Community Foundation of Albany, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Community Research for Solving Problems of Senior Citizens, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Complications Found to Increase with Age, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - The Confused Elderly Patient, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Congress for National Health Newsletter - Banquet Honors, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Correlation of Mental Status and Fasting Blood Sugar in the Elderly, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Correspondence - Colleague Correspondence, 1944; 1954; 1956-1957; 1959 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Correspondence - Colleague Correspondence, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Correspondence - Colleague Correspondence, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Correspondence - Colleague Correspondence, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Correspondence - Colleague Correspondence, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Correspondence - Colleague Correspondence, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Correspondence - Colleague Correspondence, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Correspondence - Colleague Correspondence, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Correspondence - Colleague Correspondence, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Correspondence - Colleague Correspondence, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Correspondence - Colleague Correspondence, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Correspondence - Colleague Correspondence, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Correspondence - Colleague Correspondence, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Correspondence - Colleague Correspondence, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Correspondence - Colleague Correspondence, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Correspondence - Colleague Correspondence, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Correspondence - Colleague Correspondence, 1978-1979; 1981-1983; 1986; Undated (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Correspondence - Professional Correspondence, 1948; 1954-1959 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Professional Correspondence, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Professional Correspondence, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - Professional Correspondence, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - Professional Correspondence, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Professional Correspondence, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - Professional Correspondence, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - Professional Correspondence, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - Professional Correspondence, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - Professional Correspondence, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - Professional Correspondence, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence - Professional Correspondence, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence - Professional Correspondence, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence - Professional Correspondence, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence - Professional Correspondence, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence - Professional Correspondence, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence - Professional Correspondence, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence - Professional Correspondence, 1977-1982; 1984-1985; 1987-1988; Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence - Professor Gabriel Marcel, 1970; Undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Council on Geriatric Cardiology (1 of 2), 1987-1991 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Council on Geriatric Cardiology (2 of 2), 1987-1991 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - A Critique of Cardiac Rehabilitation, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Curriculum Vitae and Medical Publications - Updated, Undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Daxid, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Death and Dying in the Life Cycle: An Educational Model for Health Professionals, Undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Deceptive Signs, Altered Drug Responses Held Common Pitfalls in Managing MI in Elderly Patient, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Dedication Ceremony for the Gerontology Research Center Building, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Department of Mental Hygiene - Division of M.H. Resources and Policy Planning, 1954-1990 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Effects of Physical Exertion on the Accelerogram In Young, Middle-Aged, and Old Subjects without Clinical Heart Disease, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Eleventh Annual Cardiovascular Teaching Day, 1975 December 4 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Exercise and the Aging Process, Undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Exercise Can Prevent Aging, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Facing the Facts, 1976; Undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Fitness and Exercise for Wellness and Health: A Day in the Life of Dr. H, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Fifth Annual Norman Sharrer Memorial Symposium, 1985 September 21 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - For Grandparents - Wonders and Worries, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Fundiscope Exam Clue to Severity, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - The Future Role of the Private Agency in Rehabilitation Services, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Gallery Proof: Who's Who in Technology, Undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Geriatric Fellowship Proposal, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Geriatric Hypertension: Treating the Whole Patient, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Geriatrics as a Specialty, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Gerontological Society - Clinical Medicine Section, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Gerontological Society - Officers of the Professional Sections and Section Representatives to the Council, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Gerontological Society - Publications Committee, 1965-1969 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - The Gerontologist - Editorial Board, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Goals of Comprehensive Health Care in Advanced Old Age, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Good Health Can Lead to Independence, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Growing Older, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Harris on Health, 1980-1983; Undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Healthy American Fitness Leaders Award Nomination Form, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Heart Association of Albany County, 1962-1965 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - The Heart in the Old Age, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Hemochromatosis and the Heart, 1981; 1984 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Holiary: The Fourth Phase of Medicine, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Honorary Membership - New York State Society of Internal Medicine, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Honorary Staff Member - Albany Memorial Hospital, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - How Exercise Changed One Doctor's Life - And What It Can Do for You, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Human Side of Business Machines, Undated (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Hypertension in the Aged: Course, Diagnosis, and Treatment, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Information Relative to Provider-Based Physicians for the Cost Reporting Period Ending December 31, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Internist Observer, 1970 (Flat-file 2)
  - An Interview With Dr. Karl Jaspers on Wisdom and Life - By Raymond Harris, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Invitation - Presidents Commission on Physical Fitness, Undated (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - JWB Mission to Latin America, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - The Key Reporter - St. Peters Hospital, 1973; 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Kramer Foundation, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Laboratory Problems - RESTRICTED, 1960; 1962; 1964; 1973 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Lawrence Frankel Foundation, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - LB-500 Segontin, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - The L.M.D Syndrome, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - The Logic of Words, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Maintaining the Geriatrics' Patients Identity, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - The Management of Geriatric Cardiovascular Disease, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - The Management of Geriatric Cardiovascular Disease - Translated, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Management of Postmenopausal Cardiac Patient, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Managing the Geriatric Patient, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Medical Consultant - RESTRICTED, 1954-1982 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Medical Legislative Digest, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Medical Publications, Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Medical Roles in Institutions for the Aged, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Medical Society of the County of Albany Membership, 1949 April 27 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Medical Society of the State of New York, 1997-2000 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Medical Staff Meetings - Albany Medical College of Union University, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Medical Tribune: Advances in Medical Care of the Elderly, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Medical Tribune: Longevity and Life Expectancy, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Medicine Catches Up with the Sports Boom, 1980 (Flat-file 3)
  - Memorial Hospital - Completion of Records, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - A Memorial Tribute to Edward L. Bortz, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - The Microcirculation in Clinical Medicine, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - A Model Curriculum for an Elective Course in Geriatrics, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Model for a Graduate Geriatric Program at University Medical School, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Myxedema Heart Disease: Case of Massive Pericardial Effusion with Dramatic Response to Cytomel, Undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - National Graduate University - College of Human Services - Advisory Group Meeting Minutes, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Nations Outstanding Young Men of 1954 Contest (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - New Goals for the Gray Lady, 1952; 1962; Undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - New Medical Horizon in Aging, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - New Release Guidance Sheets, Undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - New York Academy of Sciences Membership, 1953 August 13 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - New York State Affiliate, American Heart Association, 1981; 1983 (Box 3, Folder 31)